OLIN KIRKLAND

Sternbergstraße 10 93047 Regensburg, Germany

plakat@live.com; +49 162 3720898

www.olinkirk.land

SUMMARY

I'm a German-American software developer living in Regensburg, Germany. I've freelanced in Edinburgh and Berlin, worked as an educator in Washington D.C. and Texas, and filled the role of the lead programmer for an exhibit design company in Houston. As a programmer, I've taken on leadership roles on software projects and worked closely with researchers, graphic designers, and animators on tight schedules.

SKILLS

- Programming: ActionScript, Flex, C#, JavaScript
- IDEs: IntelliJ IDEA, Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse, FlashDevelop, Flash Builder
- Adobe Suite: Adobe Animate Professional, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop
- *Communication:* Fluent in English and German
- Worth Mentioning: Git, JSON, XML, RegEx

EDUCATION

George Mason University, Fairfax, VA, United States

Completed coursework towards a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science September 2011 – June 2013

Oakton High School, Fairfax, VA, United States

Graduated with Advanced Placement September 2007 – June 2011

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DALLMEIER, Regensburg, BY, Germany

Flex Developer, May 2018 - Present

- Work closely with other programmers and designers to build intuitive user interfaces
- Develop various interactive modules for displaying and visualizing data
- Technologies: Adobe Air, Flex

HOUSTON MUSEUM OF NATURAL SCIENCE, Houston, TX, United States

Contract Interactive Developer, September $2017-May\ 2018$

- Developed interactive touch screen applications and kiosks for deployment in the Houston Museum of Natural Science, one of the most popular museums in the United States
- Worked closely with curators to build content rich exhibits that entertain and inform visitors
- Organized and led meetings with museum docents and volunteers
- Constructed and maintained a custom database for researchers building a dataset of European castles
- Designed and developed an interactive kiosk using LEAP Motion technology
- Technologies: Adobe Air, Adobe Flash, C#, LEAP Motion

PAUL BERNHARD EXHIBIT DESIGN AND CONSULTING, Houston, TX, United States

Lead Programmer, August 2015 – April 2018

- Developed interactive touch screen museum applications and information kiosks
- Directed the organization and implementation of museum content in custom applications
- Wrote programs to interface with and visualize data from custom hardware (sensors such industrial

joysticks and Arduinos)

- Produced maps based on custom data sets using industry standard GIS tools
- Programmed visualizations for data from a wide variety of formats and sources including data from RESTful APIs related to energy sectors and extensive industry data sets
- Built APIs to interface with custom lighting controls
- Communicated with engineers, graphic designers, and researchers during development
- Created concepts and layouts as detailed storyboards for graphic designers to build on
- Managed the deployment of applications to their intended hardware
- Technologies: Adobe Air, Flex, C#, Unity, HTML, JavaScript, Adobe Flash, Arduino

ZENITH LEARNING, Houston, TX, United States

Teacher, January 2017 – June 2017

- Created lesson plans and activities relating to subjects including mechanical engineering and robotics
- Supervised, instructed, and assisted students in a classroom setting

RENAISSANCE CHILD, Arlington, VA, United States

Technology Lead and Camp Instructor, April 2015 – September 2015

- Created lesson plans and activities relating to mechanical engineering, programming, and robotics
- Supervised, instructed, and assisted students in a classroom setting

ODESK.COM

Freelance Interactive Media Developer and Graphic Designer, June 2013 – April 2015

- Developed and implemented graphics and layouts for company applications
- Maintained an organized archive of versions and products
- Technologies: HTML, JavaScript, Adobe Air, Adobe Flash

GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY HOUSING DEPARTMENT, Fairfax, VA, United States

Web and Flash Developer, January 2012 - May 2013

- Created concepts and sample layouts to run by management
- Technologies: HTML, JavaScript, Adobe Flash

PERSONAL PROJECTS

REALMS

Procedural World and Map Simulation, 2019

MAZE

Procedural Maze Solving Game, 2017

ALTAR (GLOBAL GAME JAM 2016)

Multiplayer Platformer, 2016

ENTROPY

Physics-based Arcade Game, 2015

SWEET DREAMS (GLOBAL GAME JAM 2014)

Platformer, 2014

AMBER WORLD

Turn Based Role-Playing Game, 2013